    <ConfigSection>
    <!--************************   Global Config Options   *********************************
    *   Below are options to control the general behavior of all distributions.
    *************************************************************************************-->

        <OptionNumeric name='oreFreq' default='1' min='0' max='5' displayState='shown' displayGroup='groupGeneral'>
            <Description> 
                A global multiplier for the frequency of all ore distributions. 
            </Description>
            <DisplayName>Ore Frequency</DisplayName>
        </OptionNumeric>

        <OptionNumeric name='oreSize' default='1' min='0' max='5' displayState='shown' displayGroup='groupGeneral'>
            <Description> 
                A global multiplier for the size of all ore distributions. 
            </Description>
            <DisplayName>Ore Deposit Size</DisplayName>
        </OptionNumeric> 
       
        <OptionChoice name='debugMode' default='false' displayState='shown_dynamic' displayGroup='groupGeneral'>
            <Description> 
                Enable/disable debugging mode, which allows the use of in-game wireframe models and console commands.  Also controls the visibility of some advanced options.
            </Description>
            <Comment>           
                This is a "magic" option - it has meaning outside of this file in the COG engine itelf.  You can change the value, obviously, but do not remove the option itself or change the possible values.
            </Comment>
            <DisplayName>Debugging Mode</DisplayName>
            <Choice value='true' displayValue='On'/>
            <Choice value='false' displayValue='Off'/>
        </OptionChoice> 
        
        <OptionNumeric name='deferredPopulationRange' default='16' displayGroup='groupGeneral'>
            <Description> 
                Radius (in blocks) around a chunk must be generated before COG will add ores to it. 
            </Description>
            <Comment>
                This is a "magic" option - it has meaning outside of this file in the COG engine itelf.  You can change the value, but do not remove the option itself or change the allowed range.  Changing this value is really not recommended unless you know what you are doing.
            </Comment>
            <DisplayState>:= if(?debugMode,"shown","hidden")</DisplayState>
            <DisplayName>Deferred Chunk Gen. Range</DisplayName>
            <Min>0</Min>
            <Max>128</Max>
            <DisplayIncrement>16</DisplayIncrement>
        </OptionNumeric> 
        
        <OptionChoice name='vanillaOreGen' default='true' displayGroup='groupGeneral'>
            <Description> 
                Enable/disable the vanilla ore generators for coal, iron, gold, redstone, lapis lazuli, and diamond.  
            </Description>
            <Comment>     
                This is a "magic" option - it has meaning outside of this file in the COG engine itelf. You can change the value, but do not remove the option itself.  Recommended values are True/On for new worlds and False/Off for pre-1.4.2 worlds (for compatibility).
            </Comment>
            <Comment>
                This option completely prevents these ores from being spawned by the vanilla terrain generator. It is more efficient than a Substitute distribution, which lets the generator place an ore and then removes it.  However, for technical reasons this option cannot disable vanilla emerald generation. It also has mixed results with mod generation - mods that recycle the vanilla generator get disabled, while those that use their own do not.  Finally, it is an "all-or-nothing" approach that doesn't distinguish between ore types or world properties.  For these reasons this option defaults to "true", and a Substitute distribution is used below to selectively remove the vanilla ore deposits as needed.
            </Comment>
            <DisplayState>:= if(?debugMode,"shown","hidden")</DisplayState>
            <DisplayName>Vanilla Ore Gen.</DisplayName>
            <Choice value='true' displayValue='On'/>
            <Choice value='false' displayValue='Off'/>
        </OptionChoice> 
        
        <OptionChoice name='drawWireframes' default='true' displayGroup='groupGeneral'>
            <Description> 
                Default wireframe state for distributions.  
            </Description>
            <Comment>    
                Enabling this is only one of the requirements to actually use wireframes - debugging mode must be on and the client must have Forge and COG installed, cheats enabled, and the wireframe rendering mode set up.       
            </Comment>
            <DisplayState>:= if(?debugMode,"shown","hidden")</DisplayState>
            <DisplayName>Distribution Wireframes</DisplayName>
            <Choice value='true' displayValue='On'/>
            <Choice value='false' displayValue='Off'/>
        </OptionChoice>     
        
        <OptionChoice name='debugDist' default='false' displayGroup='groupGeneral'>
            <Description> Enable/disable testing distributions. </Description>
            <DisplayState>:= if(?debugMode,"shown","hidden")</DisplayState>
            <DisplayName>Test Distributions</DisplayName>
            <Choice value='true' displayValue='On'/>
            <Choice value='false' displayValue='Off'/>
        </OptionChoice>   

        <OptionChoice name='advOptions' default='false'
                      displayState='shown_dynamic'
                      displayGroup='groupGeneral'>
          <Description> 
            Enable/disable advanced frequency and size settings for
            individual distributions. 
          </Description>
          <DisplayName>Advanced Options</DisplayName>
          <Choice value='true' displayValue='On'/>
          <Choice value='false' displayValue='Off'/>
        </OptionChoice>
       
    </ConfigSection>

